- Email, and so getting logged onto an email,
they had to, we had to create an email.
And then obviously I can't be too mean,
my vice president of technology isn't here,
but, so, but no, he knows.
He knows.
And so the thing is,
once we then moved onto the next step
of logging onto an email,
well, we had multifactor authentication,
and at the time we had two of them.
And so we're safer now.
And so this is not a bash towards you, Arla,
but my base is, you know,
it was not an easy process of onboarding students.
And so thinking that we could onboard 14 students
that had never touched a computer before in their life
in an hour and a half period of time,
not gonna happen.
I mean, and I say that genuinely
that we changed the next group
that we onboarded two weeks later.
We did one-on-one.
And so we made changes there.
As we continue to look
at like the development side of things,
of what we're doing
with our competency-based education program,
I mentioned we're the very first competency-based program
in agriculture in California.
There was no one that we could compare to
and specifically like the processes
of what we were doing.
It is a non-credit CBE program currently.
There was no transcripts
that we could really copy off of or use.
So we had to develop transcripts,
and we're still developing transcripts.
We've actually, we have developed a competency-based
education transcript, but ensuring that, you know,
as we look at scalability of programs,
we know some of the students not only will take
the competency-based access system certificate,
but they'll also take potentially a for-credit program.
And so ensuring that if students are requesting transcripts,
they don't have to--
we're trying to eliminate one less click for them
so that if they wanna request transcripts,
it spits it all out onto two or three documents.
That hasn't been an easy process.
And so when we're looking at some of those barriers
from a systematic side of things,
we're still working on that.
And we're, we meet weekly;
we have several different work groups that are part of that.
When we look at the barriers for students,
that's what this specific program has been all about
was how can we remove barriers for students.
The process of applying to a community college
in California is not simple.
We have a wellbeing program at the college,
and I applied to be a student at Merced College
a couple, a few months ago.
I was kind of lost,
and I kind of sit back and I was like,
"How are my students that have never touched a computer
before gonna get through this?"
And so in some programs,
the ag tech program specifically,
it's very, very one-on-one with our support systems.
We know that's not an option for all students, though.
And so how can we cut down barriers for students?
One other barrier that I wanna share is,
you know, when the students get into our program
and they get through their very first competency,
which is digital literacy,
that's our major stress for some of our students.
And for some of them,
once they get halfway through that,
which, you know, could take roughly six to eight hours--
it could take six to eight hours for folks
that are traditional, know how to use computers.
But for some of these, it takes them two, three months.
After that, they're discouraged
and they said, "Is this how this is gonna be for the rest?"
And so we have support systems built in place.
I have two dedicated student support coordinators
that work with those students.
They're constantly calling.
They're saying, "Hey, I haven't seen that you've done
anything on Canvas for the last two weeks.
What's going on?"
"Sorry, I'm sorry, Ning, I am,
I'm in the middle of almond harvest right now.
I gotta take a step away."
"You got it.
We'll call you in another month or so."
Or we see students that,
"Hey, we see you haven't done anything
in the last couple weeks.
What's going on?"
"Well, I was scared to tell you,
but my computer broke."
And so it allows us,
those support coordinators have really allowed for us
to kind of decrease some of those barriers for the students.
Getting onto the college campus
the very first time is daunting.
And if you go to the wrong building,
you go to the wrong office,
for some of these students, they say,
"Hmm, too much.
I'm gonna go home, not gonna do it."
And so I have student support coordinators
that will meet the students at the local Starbucks
and say, "Hey, follow me in."
And so we've noticed that for a lot of these students.
So the farm laborers students,
they need more and more support.
And so, but once we get them in there
and they get some success,
they get through some of these competencies,
they find it really, really rewarding.
The one other thing is
that our industry partners have fully supported
their employees to be going through this program,
in which some of them have guaranteed
a dollar to $2 more an hour raise.
And for some of those students, that's huge.
For other students and other companies,
they've promised them to be on a supervisory role
or a managerial role, which, you know,
that's life-changing.
That's family changing.
And so it's an opportunity for us
and for those companies to really show the support
towards those students and say,
"Hey, you know, we understand that agriculture is changing."
'Cause it is.
I mean, when we look at the costs of labor,
when we talk about water efficiency,
when we talk about all these things,
things are changing.
And as we look at just, you know,
the harvesting equipment where, you know,
15 years ago we were reliant upon laborers
to handpick our, you know,
tomatoes or our bell peppers.
Now as we continue to evolve with ag tech,
we see a lot more equipment that's being involved.
A lot more autonomous equipment.
But what the employers are telling us is,
"We don't have people that can operate that equipment."
Now, you know, we've grown,
we've invested in some of this equipment,
but now what we're finding is
we don't have people that can, you know,
operate that equipment.
And so we're essentially upskilling those farm laborers
that were traditionally on their hands and knees
into now operating, you know,
a harvesting piece of equipment
or being able to sit behind a sorter,
an optical sorter, and be able to, you know,
they're able to be upskilled on something like that.
And it makes them a lot more valuable,
and in most cases, they're gonna make more money.
- I think there's a really important piece
as you were talking
kind of went through my head multiple times.
It's all about working smarter, not harder.
It's not taking the job away;
we're just having to think differently with the work.
And I think in ag we've seen this,
and even in manufacturing,
we've seen it in the way automation's come in;
the equipment we're using is changing.
It may not be changing at the speed of like,
you know, some of the more technical worlds
of like the microchip world.
It's not going as fast as that,
but it is changing,
and the skill sets that are needed,
some of those foundational, are needed there regardless.
And then you need to think about how that technology
is layering on top of it.
Our best mechanics come from our shop floor
because they understand the equipment that they run,
and then they become that qualified mechanic afterwards.
I was laughing about the two-factor authentication
because the other day I was trying to get SAP's Concur
on my phone app working.
You should have seen me,
and I work in technology a lot,
and I was like, "It is not working,
it's not going to my authenticator,
it's not going to this, what am I supposed to do?"
And it's like, "I can't go to my website
'cause I'm not supposed to be on it,
but I need to book a flight."
And it was like, "This is crazy."
And we get that in our everyday life,
and that frustration in our everyday life,
it's one of the biggest things
is about how to help that employee
and that barrier of how do we make it easier for them
as they're accessing this technology?
How do we give them the scary help guides,
I'm gonna call it,
rather than admitting that they don't know it?
How do we give them that subtle support?
So, you know, "Where do I get to learn about Excel
and how do a pivot table?
Oh, I can stick it in ChatGPT now, yay.
But how do I do it as well?"
Like, where are those tools
and leading them to those to help?
And that's what we found ourselves
in a learning function thinking about,
like, how do we pepper those in
to those resistors or also just like,
"Hey, this tool has some great ways
to go in there and find out how to..."
It doesn't mean it can do it all for you.
And I think that's what we've seen
as industry changes.
We've also seen the fear of,
"This is not my job, I dunno how to do it,
and this is not what I know,"
and we've had to just support them.
And sometimes it's that handholding
just to like how to turn that computer on,
how to navigate the screen,
or as we're putting in new technology into a line,
"This is not removing a job,
it's gonna kind of make your life easier
or you're gonna be doing less manual work."
That was probably the biggest
as we brought in automatic depalletizers and palletizers.
No longer are we manually moving rack stacks of glass;
the robots are doing it.
So now we're watching to see for the following.
Now, sometimes the quality defects
don't get caught quite as quickly,
but it's okay,
we still have to then build in those things.
So I think that's it.
It's really about, it's enhancing, it's not removing.
And I think that's the same with AI,
that's the same with, you know,
new technologies coming in.
It's about enhancement
and the foundational thinking still
and the building of critical thinking
when it comes to the more complex sides of it.
- Thank you both so much for sharing.
So many follow-up questions,
but I do wanna leave some time and space
for the audience to see
if there were any burning questions
that you wanted to ask our panelists
in the last several minutes we have.
Please go ahead.
- [Member] I just wonder, so you talked big picture,
but I'm just curious always
if you would all speak to how you use AI tools
in your own daily work.
Is it just Copilot through email?
Is anyone building Canvas?
Just how does it help you all make your life easier
to do the work you just described?
- Yeah, I do use it.
I use ChatGPT, and I am not afraid to say I do.
And I encourage a lot of my other colleagues
to utilize it as well
because it makes me work smarter.
Obviously, you know,
I've built up the memory on some of these things,
and so I've, you know, mentioned to my colleagues,
"Just don't, you know, when you ask a question,
make sure you proof it."
But as the more and more I've utilized it,
it makes my job much more simpler.
I've been working on several different MOUs,
and so being able to put a draft MOU together
and then work through it on other components,
I mean, it makes me--
I know we talked about, you know,
we work a lot smarter, not harder--
and so I use it every single day.
- Yeah, it's funny,
I used to lead the instructional design team
as one of my priorities,
and we talked a lot about utilization of that
when we were designing training
and where do you utilize AI to create it versus not.
And you can create a whole training program in AI,
but you still have to go back in
and make sure and validate.
And I think that's what we found
is we are using it as a foundation,
but it doesn't mean it's the final.
We are using AI voice
because that is so much easier.
It's so less time-consuming.
When you find the AI voice platforms
that work and sound real,
we're like with it, we'll use it.
And there's a couple that we've used for that
where we're like, "We like this AI,"
but we've purchased it for a month to see if we like it.
And then if we like the voices that are coming through
and they're not sounding robotic,
I love not having to record voice.
We'll have to listen to me.
I'm like, "Good.
I don't have to walk past someone's computer
where they're listening and I'm like, ugh, that's me."
So it's great in that side of it.
We've been able to remove,
and it's reduced time for our team members.
We've used it for translation for certain things,
but we've been very careful
'cause we usually want it court-appointed.
But it has helped where we don't need court-appointed.
And again, there's iffy around Spanish translations
and the ag industry Spanish; it's very different.
We use it,
I use it a lot with data to play with data and see
or if I've got multiple documents to summarize,
like, "Can you find me the trends?
Can you find me...?"
Again, I still need to do some reading.
So in my spare time, I guess
I do quite a lot of work for the state
in different areas,
and sometimes I get 150 pages to read,
and sometimes just putting it in
to see what the key themes are is really useful.
The other day I used it to write a marketing campaign.
I used Copilot to write a marketing campaign
for some training courses we created,
and I could literally,
'cause my creative brain was not there,
and I could literally pick the instructor guides.
So the facilitator guides that have the speed,
have the scripts and the timing
and the pictures of the slides,
and ask it to pull out like key learnings
or, "What are key business purposes behind this training?"
Even though I kind of knew
'cause I knew the purpose 'cause it was a project,
but I couldn't get creative in the writing of it.
It pulled pieces out for me
and made me think differently around it.
But it's about how you use it,
and that's how I'm finding it is, like,
I'm using it, but then I have to use my brain against it.
Or I have to--
I had one where the learning management system
was dumping a load of data,
and I was like, "I don't have time to pivot table this
into something pretty or to try and work it out."
We found that if we dump it into Copilot
and give it the correct prompts,
it would summarize all of it, and it was fantastic.
It was about movement data of team members,
and I had 500 team members.
I was looking at movement data of,
it was hurting my head,
and it was about timing, roles,
what was their progression from A to B to C.
And that did it for me much quicker
than it would've taken me to do it in another way
'cause it was data that you had to think about,
like, the formatting and all of that.
So I don't say I would use it 50% of my time at all,
but I use it in and out as I need to,
and I found I've had to get braver about it,
if that makes sense.
Like I've had to be like,
"I'm just gonna try it
if it doesn't give me anything."
But there are some things where I'm like,
"It doesn't make sense.
It's quicker just to write it than it is to put it in."
Whereas I know some people are putting everything in
and spitting it out and then submitting,
and I'm like, "Oh, I can tell you that's not your writing."
You know, just by the way it reads,
like every educator knows
when they can tell for plagiarism.
- "I hope this email finds you well."
- Yeah, exactly.
Or some of the others.
And I'm like, "Okay, this is..."
But I was writing something last night
and I was like, "I'm not that persuasive.
I wanted to make it persuasive to them.
I wanted them to like recognize something."
I was like, "I'm gonna put it in there."
It was an external thing,
and I was like, "I want them to realize."
And so I put it into chat,
I put it into Copilot and said,
"Summarize it for me."
I love it for meetings and summaries of meetings.
And we've been told, "Don't use Otter.ai."
We used to use Otter.ai for a lot of focus group work
and like facilitation things,
and they were talking about data security,
I have no idea.
They're now like, "Go to Copilot."
So that side, and I also watched a team,
and this is really creative.
They were a high-potential learning pro--
high-potential group,
and they were designing a product for market.
They got by, "Here's the market we're looking at,
here are the consumers we're looking at."
It came up with the packaging ideas for these products,
and it was amazing in what it did in like,
and they were using ChatGPT,
and it was amazing to see the designs
that were coming out of it.
They still needed a bit of tweaking,
and like one group said,
"Oh, I can tell that was an AI image."
And I was like, "How?"
And they kind of identified a couple of things
in that like demographic.
But it really helped us to like think outside the box
to something that's new.
That's that.
So I think it really depends,
but I would say people are using it 25% of the time.
Those that are using it more than that,
there's ways of knowing
that they're using it more than that,
and it's reflecting.
People are like, "Oh, I think just stuck it in Copilot,"
you know, in that way.
Does that help?
- I'll add from my perspective at Jobs for the Future,
I've been, I've sort of switched my philosophy
where I used to start off
with having different AI tools like Copilot
or ChatGPT create a first draft.
And I was realizing I was getting a lot of gobblygook
that didn't make a lot of sense.
So I've started off with drafting something myself
and then giving really specific commands of,
"Make it more persuasive, make it more pithy,
make it for a C-level executive,
put it in this voice."
- I asked it to make it non-AI the other day
after it being persuasive.
I said, "Now make it more human," or, "less AI."
It was amazing. It did it.
And I was like, "Okay, that sounds more like me.
You've taken it back from here to here."
But it's almost not being afraid.
Yeah, but I'm the same.
I don't write the first draft in it.
Yeah, it's the fine, fine-tuning.
- Yeah, that's exactly it.
But I think we're coming up on time.
Maybe the only thing standing between you and your break,
but wanted to really share my gratitude
to both Rebecca and Cody for sharing.
I think this was a really insightful panel,
so thank you so much.
Round of applause. (audience applauding)
And happy to answer more questions if folks have them.
Feel free to come up and see us.